

Brandon Ellington

Networked+Social Systems Engineer

June 25 1993

United States

(206) 450 - 1343

branjam.dev

branjam4@gmail.com

About me -

Using metacognition to link big picture insights with individual experiences, I make critical connections to help groups move forward.

Python **Functional Programming Object-Oriented Programming Database Management DevOps**

SQL*3 emacs*3 org-mode*3 shell \star 2.8 scheme \star 2.5 C(++) \star 2.5 clojure * 2.1 php * 2 java * 1.3

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

interests

Empowering organizations to make change through improving mental health, physical well-being, and the relationship with our environment using data and technology.

education

2017-2020 Bachelor of Science

Majoring in Computer Science

2017-2020 Bachelor of Arts

Business Concentration

The Evergreen State College

The Evergreen State College

GitHub

Evergreen Program:

experience

2018-2019 CRM Lynda.com Fellowship Shadowed the Assistant Director of Advancement Services. Learned how

The Evergreen State College, Advancement

to use the Blackbaud Raiser's Edge Constituent Relationship Management System. Assisted with data management and building complex database

query views through SQL and Excel. Served during campaign events.

2017-2018 Office Manager Services and Activities Fee Allocation Board Reduced budget intake, processing from 5 hours/week to <1 hour by moving from paper budgets to Google Drive, Sheets. Trained 12 board members on the function and operations of the Board.

June 2017 Enterprise Software Internship Computing and Communications Dept. (Evergreen) Evaluation from my field supervisor, Senior Systems Analyst: "Brandon's communication skills were particularly valuable to the team. He facilitated requirements gathering sessions with the users in my absence...He was always willing to adjust coding styles and practices to the team approach. He was the only intern I've ever trusted to lead sprint planning sessions, because he had developed the appropriate soft skills, and because he seemed to grasp the Agile process."

projects

June 2020 Containerized Integrated Development Environment

See project at https://github.com/branjam4/doom-emacs-docker.git.

Dec. 2018 Authorship- Computational Linguistics Project

Computational Linguistics

Evaluation from faculty: "Brandon worked with four other students to complete the project on computationally identifying the author of a text. Their well-coordinated final presentation provided an organized overview of their process and a discussion of both obstacles and successes. Brandon provided leadership and empowerment to newer coders by guiding the group towards a process that emphasized an algorithm and descriptive understandings of what the code needed to accomplished, as well as developing the actual code and some of the details of testing strategies. The group embodied a learning community by making a commitment to make sure that everyone understood the algorithm and the code. Brandon also demonstrated their collaborative learning skills by helping two other groups on the project."

June 2017 Sentiment Analysis- Data Mining Project United Way of Pierce County

Worked with a team of five to leverage sentiment analysis algorithms, collecting data in the form of tweets and posts from Facebook, to quantify how receptive Pierce County residents were to United Way's reports on understanding and assisting Pierce County's ALICE (Asset Limited, Income Constrained, Employed) population. I also went a little further and familiarized myself with the methodology and data used to identify our target demographics, which helped my team put our observations into perspective. My group recognized me as the member who went the extra mile in order to connect with our client and fill their needs.